# ANKIT JAGTAP

Boston, MA | (857)250-9984 | Email | Portfolio | LinkedIn

### **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience in launching and managing high-impact products; slashed manual efforts by an impressive 70%, resulting in annual savings of \$1M for an investment banking client; elected as the Vice President of Technology leading to >50% improvements in success metrics and advocating for 18,000+ users to fuel product advancement.

# **EDUCATION**

Northeastern University Boston, MA

Master of Science in Information Systems

August 2023

Relevant Coursework: Business Analysis, Planning & Managing Systems, Enterprise Software Design

University of Mumbai India

Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Telecommunication

June 2018

Relevant Coursework: Operating Systems, Structured Programming Approach

## **EXPERIENCE**

Northeastern University

Research Assistant

Boston, MA
September 2023 - Present

• Contributed to the extension of the Unity-based Dinobots game, emphasizing AI and Prompt Engineering

- Developed a **React**, **Typescript**, and **Tailwind** CSS-based web project for the **ArtLab** website by creating scripts to access
- Retrieved content from social media platforms, leveraging official APIs and scraping techniques
- Collaborated on the creation of a graphic novel using generative AI by tutorials on the AI-driven creative process

### **Graduate Student Government**

Boston, MA

Vice-President of Technology

May 2022 - May 2023

- Managed a team of 7+ members from Technology committee for Go-Live and post-implementation support serving 18,000+ users
- Administered M365 products by setting up Microsoft Bookings page on website and managing Microsoft Teams, Zoom and Slack
- Achieved >50% improvement in KPIs by tracking and analyzing team performance and making data-driven decisions
- Identified and solved 15+ customer pain points through user research, UX design and product roadmap development
- Implemented risk management plan to mitigate 20+ potential risks and minimize negative impacts

### **Charles River Development**

Burlington, MA

SaaS Operations Co-op

August 2022 - December 2022

- Engineered 10+ batch automation features for the SaaS Onboarding team using Python, Django, and Jinja templates
- Automated Azure Active Directory authentication for user groups across 3 network domains and integrated RESTful API
- Analyzed data and identified 5+ areas for improvement and initiated 3+ process improvements to streamline operations
- Constructed a scalable PostgreSQL schema using ORM, optimizing query performance by 30%

#### **Hexaware Technologies**

India

Associate Software Engineer

July 2018 - July 2021

- Developed web portal for **legacy mainframe** system and migrated UI framework using **HTML5** and **CSS3** concepts
- Formulated reusable Angular components in Agile methodology to display dashboards, enhancing efficiency >80%
- Automated obsolete trade settlement process reducing manual efforts >70% and saving \$1M/year
- Facilitated in multivariate testing, A/B testing, and led full-scale product launch and rollouts resulting 60% less defects
- Collaborated with stakeholders on scope trade-off decisions, change management for product rollouts, and UAT

#### **PROJECTS**

### **Conference Funding Process Automation (ServiceNow, Jira, Google Analytics)**

July 2023 - August 2023

- Implemented E2E project management strategies, resulting in 25% reduction in project timeline by maintaining quality standards
- Cut processing time from 3+ months to a maximum of 3 weeks, optimizing response and resource allocation
- Utilized ADKAR model for change management, fostering smooth adoption and ensuring alignment with stakeholder needs

### **Automated Ticketing System (Microsoft Office, Valero, Trello)**

January 2023 - May 2023

- Generated a comprehensive 12-month project plan for implementing the Automated Ticketing System
- Prepared and analyzed **RACI matrix** to clarify each **80**+ project activities
- Processed a Gantt chart to visually represent project schedule and tasks over 12 months